http://www.chch.ox.ac.uk/alumni/privacy-notice

CollegeCathedralVisitors
Go BackCollege HomeStudy HereTeaching and ResearchCurrent StudentsCollege Life BlogAlumniLibrary and Archives
Go BackStudy Here HomeUndergraduatesGraduatesKey ContactsChat to students
Go BackUndergraduates HomeWhy Apply to Christ Church?Choosing a CourseHow to ApplyOpen DaysWorking with Students and TeachersStudent Ambassadors
Go BackWhy Apply to Christ Church? HomeFinancial SupportAccommodation and MealsFacilitiesSocial Spaces and Student SocietiesStudents with DisabilitiesEngagement in the Wider Community
Go BackFinancial Support HomeFunding Your Studies
Go BackHow to Apply HomeExplore Beyond SchoolPersonal StatementAdmissions TestsInterviewsAdmissions Feedback
Go BackExplore Beyond School HomePython ChallengesAn Oral History Project
Go BackPython Challenges HomePython Challenge 1Python Challenge 2Python Challenge 3Python Challenge 4Python Challenge 5
Go BackOpen Days Home
Go BackWorking with Students and Teachers HomeChrist Church HorizonsAim for OxfordAccess and Outreach PartnershipsIntoUniversity
Go BackGraduates HomeGraduate Study at Christ ChurchGraduate Selection CriteriaGraduate AccommodationGraduate Employment
Go BackChat to students Home
Go BackTeaching and Research HomeTeaching and Research StaffResearch and Teaching Subject AreasResearch at Christ ChurchTower PoetrySenior Common Room
Go BackResearch at Christ Church HomeAfrican HouseRecently Published Books
Go BackTower Poetry HomeEnter the Tower Poetry CompetitionPrevious CompetitionsTower Poetry Summer SchoolsTower Poetry turns 21Poetry OutreachBooks and Publications
Go BackSenior Common Room HomeLinks for Senior Members
Go BackCurrent Students HomeNotices and Useful ResourcesThe Academic OfficeThe Censors' OfficeHealth and WelfareTerm DatesExaminationsSportsCommon RoomsDegree Days and Graduating for Current StudentsSustainability & Green Impact
Go BackNotices and Useful Resources HomeThe Blue Book 2020-2021Room CapacitiesIT Facilities
Go BackThe Blue Book 2020-2021 HomeIntroductionGeneral InformationStudent regulations during the pandemicInformation for new students and student arrivalsStudying at Christ ChurchHealth and welfareLife at Christ ChurchFacilitiesRecreation and SocietiesFees and FinanceResources and LinksNon-Academic Disciplinary ProcedureAcademic Disciplinary Procedure
Go BackHealth and Welfare HomeCollege Chaplain and Welfare CoordinatorStudents with DisabilitiesWelfare Support in the UniversityHealth ServicesWelfare Videos
Go BackSports HomeThe Boat ClubStudent SocietiesEngagement in the Wider Community
Go BackThe Boat Club HomeCommitteeCoaching Team 2018/19RegattaBoat Club ConstitutionHistory of the Boat ClubChCh BC OlympiansBoat Club Crew Lists
Go BackHistory of the Boat Club HomeEarly Days of the Boat ClubW.A.L. "Flea" FletcherCherryThe House at HenleyImages from the Hodgkin ArchiveImages from the Boat Club Archive
Go BackChCh BC Olympians HomeChCh BC most recent Olympic Medallist
Go BackCommon Rooms Home
Go BackAlumni HomeSupport Christ Churche-Matters40 Years of Women at the HouseAlumni BenefitsAlumni EventsAlumni PublicationsThe American Friends of Christ ChurchChrist Church AssociationStay in Touch
Go BackSupport Christ Church HomeOur ProjectsLegaciesRecognising Your GiftHow To Give
Go BackOur Projects HomeTOMCOVID-19 Student Support FundComputer Science: A Centre of ExcellenceRenovating Peckwater QuadFamily ProgrammeBoat Club SocietyCathedral Music TrustThe Andrew Chamblin FundMentoring and Careers
Go BackTOM HomeBecome a member of TOM
Go BackRecognising Your Gift HomeTOMCrankstart SocietyBoard of Benefactors1546 SocietyBoat Club Society
Go Backe-Matters Homee-Matters November 6th 2020e-Matters October 23rd 2020e-Matters September 30th 2020e-Matters September 8th 2020e-Matters August 18th 2020e-Matters July 20th 2020e-Matters June 30th 2020e-Matters June 12th 2020e-Matters May 28th 2020e-Matters May 14th 2020e-Matters April 30th 2020e-Matters April 16th 2020e-Matters April 3rd 2020
Go Back40 Years of Women at the House HomeWomen at the HouseAlumni Poetry
Go BackAlumni Benefits HomeGaudies
Go BackAlumni Publications HomeChrist Church MattersThe Annual ReportChrist Church History
Go BackChrist Church Association HomeMentoring and CareersVolunteersAssociation Committee
Go BackStay in Touch HomeSubscribe to Alumni CommunicationsContact the Development OfficeOxford Alumni CommunityPrivacy NoticeSocial MediaAlumni and Supporter Promise
Go BackLibrary and Archives HomeUsing the LibraryCOVID-19: Information for tutorsSpecial CollectionsArchivesContacting the LibraryLibrary and Archive Staff
Go BackUsing the Library HomeThe Burn Law Library
Go BackSpecial Collections HomeDigital LibraryCataloguesHistoric CollectionsHistory of the LibraryPublicationsLibrary Research NewsExhibitions and EventsImaging Services and Photography
Go BackDigital Library HomeThe Wolsey ManuscriptsThe Lewis Carroll CollectionMusic ManuscriptsWestern ManuscriptsHebrew ManuscriptsByzantine ManuscriptsMapsEarly Printed Books
Go BackThe Lewis Carroll Collection HomeThe Making of 'Alice'Other Works by CarrollMiscellaneous Carroll MaterialPhotographyCarroll Friends and Contemporaries
Go BackMusic Manuscripts HomeThe Henry Aldrich Project
Go BackCatalogues HomeMain Catalogue (SOLO)Music CatalogueLibrary Records
Go BackHistoric Collections HomeManuscriptsPrinted BooksAllestree LibraryLord Portal CollectionOther Collections
Go BackOther Collections Home
Go BackHistory of the Library HomeProvenance PitfallsBooks & Articles about the Library
Go BackPublications HomeChrist Church Library Newsletter
Go BackExhibitions and Events HomeNature within the PagesThinking 3D: The Mathematics of SpaceWinckelmann and Curiosity in the 18th-Century Gentleman's LibrarySinging BooksMore than a House for BooksThe Miniature StageHakluyt @ 400Tudor PartbooksBeazley and Christ Church: 250 Years of Scholarship on Greek VasesRobert Hooke's MicrographiaLewis Carroll and the Art of PhotographyPrintmakers and Publishing in the 18th Century
Go BackThe Miniature Stage HomePart 1: A penny plain, twopence coloured 1811-1830Part 2: The Theatre Royal, Drawing Room 1830-1850Part 3: It's a matter of history, like 1850-1900Part 4: The poor stage is but the show-glass to a toy-shop
Go BackImaging Services and Photography HomeMicrofilms
Go BackMicrofilms HomeWilliam Wake MicrofilmsEarly Music MicrofilmsMedieval & Renaissance
Go BackArchives HomeHistory of the ArchivesContacting the ArchivistThe Archive CollectionsThe Archives BlogUseful Publications
I want to ...Chat to a student
Go BackCathedral HomeOxford's CathedralOnline WorshipOur ChoirsVisiting and LearningCathedral Blog
Go BackOxford's Cathedral HomeCathedral ServicesCathedral NewsCOVID 19: Pastoral CareCathedral EventsCollege ChapelWho's WhoSermonsLecturesYour Cathedral
Go BackWho's Who HomeCollege of Canons and wider Chapter
Go BackSermons HomeOrdinary Time 2020Lent and Easter 2020Sacred 2020Archive of Sermons
Go BackArchive of Sermons HomeAdvent, Christmas and Epiphany 2019-2020Sermons by Preacher
Go BackLectures HomeThe Great War: Its End and Effects 2019Summer Lectures 2018Summer Lectures 2019
Go BackYour Cathedral HomeFriends of the CathedralVolunteeringParish SilverThe Parishioner Pass
Go BackOnline Worship HomeAdvent and Christmas 2020Journey to Bethlehem
Go BackOur Choirs HomeCathedral ChoirCathedral SingersCollege ChoirFrideswide VoicesVisiting ChoirsCathedral Music Trust
Go BackCathedral Choir HomeAbout the Cathedral ChoirCathedral Choir Discography
Go BackAbout the Cathedral Choir HomeChoristershipsChoral ScholarshipsLay ClerkshipsOrgan ScholarshipsPeople
Go BackFrideswide Voices HomeAbout Frideswide VoicesWhat's OnContact Frideswide Voices
Go BackAbout Frideswide Voices HomeFrideswide ChoristersOrgan ScholarshipPeople
Go BackFrideswide Choristers HomeFrequently Asked QuestionsJoin Frideswide Voices
Go BackVisiting and Learning HomePractical InformationThings to SeeTours and GroupsUK School VisitsPilgrimage
Go BackThings to See HomeWar MemorialsThe OrganBell Ringers and Bells
Go BackWar Memorials HomeFirst World War MemorialSecond World War Memorial
Go BackUK School Visits HomeKey Stage 1Key Stage 2Key Stage 3 - 4Key Stage 5Virtual VisitsSpecial SchoolsCPD and INSET daysPracticalitiesJoin our Education Guides
Go BackVirtual Visits HomeResources
I want to ...View Cathedral ServicesDownload the Music List
Go BackVisitors HomePlan Your VisitPicture GalleryConferencesBed and Breakfast
Go BackPlan Your Visit HomeVisit UsTicketsThings to See and DoAccessibilityShopEvents
Go BackVisit Us HomeVisiting Information
Go BackTickets HomeWhat’s included
Go BackPicture Gallery HomeAbout the Picture GalleryCollectionsConservation and ResearchVisiting the Picture GalleryExhibitions and EventsTours, Print Room Visits and Hire
Go BackCollections HomePaintingsWorks on PaperObjects
Go BackExhibitions and Events HomeCurrent and Forthcoming ExhibitionsPast ExhibitionsEvents
Go BackConferences HomeVenue HireSpecial Interest EventBed and Breakfast
Go BackVenue Hire HomeMeeting RoomsDiningAccommodation
Go BackBed and Breakfast HomeChrist Church B&B117 St Aldates BuildingLiddell Building
Go Back117 St Aldates Building HomeHow to find 117 St Aldates Building
Go BackLiddell Building HomeHow to find Liddell Building
I want to ... Book B&B
Useful Contacts
News
I want to:
About
News
People
Support Christ ChurchOur ProjectsTOMBecome a member of TOM
COVID-19 Student Support Fund
Computer Science: A Centre of Excellence
Renovating Peckwater Quad
Family Programme
Submitted by graceholland on Thu, 2018-05-24 12:52
Christ Church Privacy Notice – Alumni, Donors and Supporters
Published 24th May 2018
Since 2008 Christ Church has been fundraising according to the ‘In Perpetuity’ Development Plan. We are working towards our goal of enduring financial independence by building up the endowment, so that in the future no part of the House will be endangered due to a deficit in the annual fund, or changes in university policy and fees. Christ Church is committed to maintaining your confidence and trust with respect to your privacy. Our principles are simple – we will be transparent about what data we are collecting about you, where that data comes from, how we use the information we hold about you, and the choices you can make.
The overarching purpose of collecting and processing your data is to provide you with the best possible experience of being an alumnus/alumna, donor, or supporter of Christ Church. It also enables us to ensure that any approaches we make to ask for your support of our alumni relations or fundraising goals are respectful, professional, and relevant to you. Christ Church and the University work closely together to ensure we engage with you in a coordinated manner.
If at any point you have questions about our privacy notice, or how we are using your data, please get in touch with us.
Privacy Notice
1. About this Privacy NoticeThe purpose of this privacy notice is to explain how Christ Church (“we”, “our”, “us”) holds and uses personal data about alumni, donors and supporters (“you”), and how we use it for alumni and supporter relations, and fundraising purposes. You can read Christ Church’s privacy notices relating to other activities and relationships here.
Development and Alumni Relations teams across the collegiate University work closely together and have aligned our policies around data privacy and our privacy notices to provide clarity for our alumni, donors and supporters. You can read the University’s privacy notices here.
2. What we doChrist Church’s Alumni Relations and Development team exists to establish and develop lifelong relationships with and amongst our alumni, donors and supporters. We’re here to help you stay connected with each other, with Christ Church and with the University of Oxford. Our communications with you will include news, research developments, events, exhibitions, collections and resources, reunions, volunteering opportunities, fundraising priorities and progress updates that are important to you.
We fundraise to ensure that, thanks to the incredible generosity of our donors, Christ Church can ensure an open and competitive admissions process based on merit, preserve the tutorial system, promote scholarship and research at all levels and honour our obligations to the buildings of the college.
3. Information we collectWe, Christ Church, collect information from you in three ways: directly from you during your ongoing relationship with us or with the University of Oxford; from publicly available sources; and/or from third parties providing us with services or acting on our behalf.
The amount of data we collect and hold depends on the frequency and nature of your interactions and engagement with us. Information may be gathered across the lifetime of our relationship with you and from many different forms of interaction.
We may hold and process the following types of personal data about you:
Biographical information, which may include:
name, title, contact details, date of birth, gender, marital status, spouse, partner and family details
for current or past students of the college and Christ Church Cathedral School: student ID, programme of study, department, college, matriculation or start date, graduation date, degree conferred
awards received whilst studying at Oxford (prizes, scholarships, accolades, bursaries); other education history and professional qualifications
involvement in sports teams, clubs and societies whilst at Oxford and subsequently
employment details (incl. salary/salary band), career history, professional activities
interests, activities and accolades, incl. honours, life achievements
profile pictures which come from publicly accessible sources (where copyright allows)
links to your public social media presence e.g. LinkedIn, Twitter, website or blog
Details of our ongoing relationship and your engagement with us, which may include:
records of your personal interactions with us (e.g. correspondence, notes of meetings or conversations)
your communication preferences; records of communications you have received from us, incl. copies of letters, emails or appeal literature sent, and of fundraising activities in which you have been included (e.g. annual fund mailings, telephone fundraising campaigns)
data obtained through cookies and similar technologies such as pixels, tags, web beacons, and other identifiers. These help us understand how you interact with our email communications, websites and other online services we provide, e.g. crowdfunding, alumni networking sites. You will find a link to the relevant cookie policy on each of our websites
your attendance (and that of your guests) on visits to, or at events across the collegiate University, including details of any payments made, and photographs, audio and video recordings in which you may be included
details of benefits and services provided to you, e.g. use of college or University libraries, Oxford University Careers Service
your connections to other alumni, students, staff, friends, groups or networks, donors and supporters within the collegiate University community
membership of college or University social media groups e.g. Facebook, LinkedIn
a record of offers of voluntary support you have made, e.g. offers of expertise, advice, mentoring, internships, coaching, accommodation/support for students visiting your area
a record of volunteer work you have undertaken
Information about your giving, which may include:
current and past donations and pledges, documentation relating to these gifts and records of the projects you have supported
financial information required to process your gifts
if you have given it, an indication of your intent to leave a legacy, including copies of Wills or sections of Wills
any requests you have made for anonymity in relation to your giving
thank you letters, donor reports provided relating to gifts you have made, correspondence and notes of meetings
plans for activities and future interactions
records of membership of any societies or groups related to your giving
your relationship to friends and patrons groups associated with, or providing support to, the collegiate University
your relationship to relevant trusts, foundations and corporates, e.g. membership on board of trustees
Information relating to your willingness or financial capacity to support our charitable objectives, which may include:
Our understanding of your likely philanthropic interests, and a note of particular projects we think may be of interest to you. This understanding may be provided by you or from information in the public domain
Information about your giving to other organisations, and other support that you provide (e.g. volunteering roles, trusteeships), where this information is given to us by you or publicly reported, and where it helps us to understand your interests and capacity to provide support
Other information which may give an indication of the scale of any potential philanthropic gift you may be able to give, such as information about earnings and assets, including property, or publicly reported estimates of wealth
Any estimate we may make regarding the potential scale of your support on the basis of the above information and your previous giving
Personal recommendations, where made by other supporters, that you may be willing and able to provide support
Sensitive personal data, which may include:
Health information, including any medical conditions - we may use health information provided by you so we can make reasonable adjustments to improve the service we are able to offer you (e.g. seating or access at an event, dietary requirements, provision of disabled parking, or allocation of accommodation). With your permission, we may also hold health data to ensure our engagement with you is based on a suitable understanding of, and care and respect for, your particular circumstances.
Criminal convictions, offences and allegations of criminal activity - we may use publicly available information concerning criminal convictions and offences or allegations of criminal activity, including money laundering or bribery offences, to carry out due diligence on donors or prospective donors in line with our guidelines on the acceptance of gifts.
Race or ethnicity, religious beliefs, sexual orientation, political opinions - we do not seek to obtain these categories of sensitive data. However, they may sometimes be inferred from other data we hold, for example, your relationships, society memberships, job titles, donations to specific causes or interests.
4. How we use your dataYour personal data are used by us for the following purposes in support of alumni and supporter relations, and fundraising:
For alumni and supporter engagement
To manage our ongoing relationship with you and to provide a record of your interactions and contributions to college life
To offer and manage a varied programme of events tailored to your interests, including networking events, subject reunions, Gaudy dinners, sports events, concerts, seminars and lectures
To ensure you are aware of the wider programme of events, lectures and seminars taking place across the collegiate University which we believe may be relevant to you and that you may have an interest in attending
To keep you up to date with news from your college, department, or other areas in which you have shown an interest, e.g. by making a donation, attending an event, or becoming a member/friend
To provide you with information about alumni benefits and services, including access to the University of Oxford Careers Service
To let you know of volunteering opportunities, including linking current students with alumni for careers advice and internships, or speaking opportunities
To provide the most relevant content and best possible user experience when you are interacting with our digital communications and platforms
To identify and profile potential volunteers, alumni ambassadors and event attendees
To accept and process commercial revenue, e.g. for merchandise or event tickets
To undertake surveys and market research
To create classifications and groupings (through manual or automated analyses) in order to best direct engagement activities
To analyse the success of our engagement activities, collect feedback, and manage complaints
For all fundraising and donor stewardship
To help ensure that our fundraising efforts are conducted as efficiently as possible, and that our approaches to potential donors are respectful, professional, and made, as far as possible, based on evidence and an understanding of what may interest you
To ask you for your support for our fundraising programmes, always mindful of fundraising best practice
To accept and process philanthropic revenue
To provide acknowledgement, recognition and stewardship of your gift
To inform you of the impact of your gift
To create classifications and groupings (through manual or automated analyses) in order to best direct fundraising activities
To support peer-to-peer fundraising campaigns
To inform fundraising, marketing and donor stewardship strategies
For fundraising for major gifts
In addition to analysing data shared with us, we may use publicly available information and recommendations from staff and supporters to identify individuals who we believe may have the interest and financial capacity to make a major gift.
Where we have reason to think a potential donor may possess an interest and financial capacity to donate, we may research and collate additional information from sources in the public domain, typically concerning a potential donor’s interests in so far as they may coincide with our work, their philanthropic activity, financial capacity and networks in order to substantiate this. We may undertake this research ourselves or use the services of a third-party partner. This new information may be added to the record of a donor or potential donor.
Where this activity is being undertaken for a new contact with whom we have no previous relationship, we will provide the individual with a link to this privacy notice as part of our initial engagement.
Information may be collated into a briefing or profile in order to assist the planning of an approach to a potential donor to discuss that individual’s interest in our work and in supporting it.
We may also carry out due diligence on potential donors using publicly available information in order to comply with our policy on the acceptance of gifts, and to fulfil our legal responsibilities.
For operational reporting, management reporting, and governance
We may use your personal data for the purposes of operational reporting, to produce management information, and for other relevant purposes relating to the governance of the college. We will use only the data required and, unless necessary, we will use anonymised or pseudonymised data.
In our external communications
Unless you request otherwise, we may publish your name in an online directory, in donor listings, as part of a guest list, or we may work with you to create press releases or case studies to be included in our publications or on our websites.
If you do not wish your data to be used in any of the ways listed above, or have any questions, please contact us using the details here.
5. When and how we share your dataWe may, from time to time, need to share your personal data within the collegiate University of Oxford or with third-parties working on our behalf. We will only do this in appropriate circumstances, by secure means, and with the relevant data sharing agreements in place. We do not, and will not, sell your data.
Third parties will only process your personal data on our instructions and where they have agreed to treat your data confidentially and to keep it secure. We only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes nor to keep your data after the processing is complete. All our third-party service providers are required to take appropriate security measures to protect your personal information in line with our policies.
Whenever your information is shared, we will always seek to share the minimum amount of information necessary to fulfil the purpose, this includes the use of anonymised or pseudonymised data where that is sufficient.
Your data may be shared in the following ways:
Within the collegiate University of Oxford
We may share your data with colleges and departments that make up the collegiate University. We will do this only where it is necessary in order to carry out any of the purposes listed in this privacy notice. For example, where the University is coordinating with one or more colleges to organise shared events to which you are invited; to manage and coordinate relationship management activities with you; or to ensure your contact information and communication preferences are up-to-date.
We may also share relevant data, in appropriate circumstances, with college or University Sports Clubs and Societies where you are (or were) a member of that club or society.
With organisations or individuals affiliated to Christ Church
We benefit from a network of organisations and individuals who volunteer their support to Christ Church. We may share relevant data with them, in appropriate circumstances, by secure means, and with the relevant data sharing agreements in place. These may include:
Volunteers offering their expertise by serving on boards or otherwise advising on or assisting with alumni or development matters
Recognised college or University alumni societies and networks, for example when they are helping to organise a dinner or host an event to which you are invited.
With partner organisations that accept gifts in support of Christ Church
The following organisations enable tax-efficient giving to Christ Church and/or the collegiate University of Oxford, from outside of the UK. Data may be shared by us with these organisations where it relates specifically to donations you have made, or have pledged to donate via these organisations.
American Friends of Christ Church (AFCC) accepts gifts in support of Christ Church. AFCC has been determined by the United States Internal Revenue Service to be a tax-exempt public charity.
Americans for Oxford, Inc. (AFO) accepts gifts in support of the collegiate University of Oxford. AFO has been determined by the United States Internal Revenue Service to be a tax-exempt public charity. The personal data you provide when making a gift to AFO are collected and processed by Oxford University’s North American Office using the shared Development and Alumni Relations System (DARS).
Swiss Friends of Oxford (SFOU)
Swiss residents can give tax efficiently to the collegiate University of Oxford. SFOU is set up as an association (Verein) under Swiss law and has a tax ruling from the canton of Zug recognising its tax-exempt status.
German Friends of Oxford University
Residents of Germany can also make tax-efficient donations to the collegiate University of Oxford via the German Friends of Oxford University without incurring any fees.
With third-party organisations engaged by Christ Church to provide services:
These include but are not limited to:
mailing houses, printers, event organisers or venues
organisations providing tools such as relationship- or event-management systems; databases and reporting/analysis tools; alumni networking or crowdfunding platforms; email or survey tools; payment services (e.g. direct debit, online donation processing)
organisations assisting with activities such as market research, marketing and communications, organisational effectiveness, strategy and planning, auditing, business intelligence and analysis, customer experience
6. How we protect your dataChrist Church takes precautions to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft and misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure and destruction through the use of appropriate administrative, physical and technical security measures.
All departments within the college have drawn up Information Asset Registers which include information on the measures in place to protect both physical and digital data during its collection, processing, and destruction (if relevant).  These Information Asset Registers (or Records of Processing Activities) will be made available on the website.
Access to your personal data is limited to those who need to process it.  As far as possible, paper records are kept in locked cabinets or cupboards which are themselves behind access-controlled doors.  The whole site is monitored during the day by custodial staff and CCTV is used in public areas.  Digital files are always password-protected and encryption is encouraged when personal data is moved.  Servers are protected by firewalls and security software.  When data is deleted, every effort is made to ensure the deletion of all copies.
Where you have provided us with your credit or debit card information, over the phone, or on a printed giving form, that data is stored securely and destroyed after your payment has been processed. Bank details used for processing Direct Debits are stored under the Direct Debit Guarantee Scheme. Online donations are processed via our third-party payment service providers and your credit or debit card information is not collected or stored by us.
Transfers of your data outside of the European Economic Area (EEA) - although most of the information we collect, store and process stays within the UK, some information may be transferred to countries outside of the European Economic Area (EEA). This may occur if, for example, one of our third-party partners’ servers are located in a country outside of the EEA. This may also occur where staff in our international offices access DARS, our shared relationship-management system.
Transfers outside of the EEA will only take place if one of the following applies:
the country receiving the data is considered by the EU to provide an adequate level of data protection
the organisation receiving the data is covered by an arrangement recognised by the EU as providing an adequate standard of data protection e.g. transfers to companies that are certified under the EU US Privacy Shield
the transfer is governed by approved contractual clauses
the transfer has your consent
the transfer is necessary for the performance of a contract with you or to take steps requested by you prior to entering into that contract
the transfer is necessary for the performance of a contract with another person, which is in your interests
the transfer is necessary in order to protect your vital interests or of those of other persons, where you or other persons are incapable of giving consent
the transfer is necessary for the exercise of legal claims
the transfer is necessary for important reasons of public interest
7. How long we keep your dataChrist Church considers its relationship with alumni, donors and supporters to be life-long and we will retain much of your data indefinitely unless you request otherwise. When determining how long we should retain your personal data we take into consideration our legal obligations and tax or accounting rules. If you have pledged a legacy gift, it will be necessary to retain your data until your gift is received, so that we can identify the gift against that pledge. When we no longer need to retain personal information, we ensure it is securely disposed of. We may keep anonymised statistical data indefinitely, but you cannot be identified from such data.
8. The legal basis for processing your dataWe will only use your personal data where the law allows us to do so. Most commonly we rely on the following legal bases for processing your personal data:
Where we have a legitimate interest to do so for purposes listed within this privacy notice. Where we use legitimate interest as the basis for our processing we have carefully considered each of the ways we process your data to ensure that we carry out our activities with a focus on the interests of our alumni, donors and supporters, and in the most efficient and effective way.
Where we need to perform the contract we have entered into with you. Information processed for this purpose includes, but is not limited to, the information you provide when you register for an event, or to enable us to process a donation.
Where we are required to comply with our legal obligations, such as for: reclamation of Gift Aid on your donations; statutory returns to the Office for Students (OfS), the Charity Commission or ICO; participation in the HESA Graduate Outcomes Survey; responses to the Charity Commission or ICO in relation to audits or official investigations; responses to FOI Requests, under the Freedom of Information Act 2000.
Where your consent is required, for example where sensitive personal data is recorded. You can withdraw your consent at any time and we will stop any processing of your personal data requiring your consent. See section 9: “Your legal rights and choices in connection with your personal data”.
Change of purpose
We will only process your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another related reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If we need to use your data for an unrelated purpose, we will seek your consent to use it for that new purpose. Please note that we may process your data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.
9. Your legal rights and choices in connection with your personal dataUnder certain circumstances, by law you have the right to:
Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a “subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of your data and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
Request correction of your data. This enables you to ask us to correct any incomplete or inaccurate information we hold about you.
Request erasure of your data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove your data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your data where you have exercised your right to object to processing (see below).
Object to processing of your data where we are processing it to meet our public interest tasks or legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground. You also have the right to object where we are processing your data for direct marketing purposes.
Request the restriction of processing of your data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your data, for example if you want us to establish its accuracy or the reason for processing it.
Request the transfer of your data to another party.
Depending on the circumstances and the nature of your request it may not be possible for us to do what you have asked, for example, where there is a statutory or contractual requirement for us to process your data and it would not be possible to fulfil our legal obligations if we were to stop. However, where you have consented to the processing, you can withdraw your consent at any time by emailing us. In this event, we will stop the processing as soon as we can. If you choose to withdraw consent it will not invalidate past processing.
If you want to exercise any of the rights described above or are dissatisfied with the way we have used your information, please contact the Database Manager.  We will seek to deal with your request without undue delay, and in any event in accordance with the requirements of the GDPR. Please note that we may keep a record of your communications to help us resolve any issues which you raise.
If you remain dissatisfied, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.
10. Contact usIf you have any questions about this privacy notice or about your personal data, or if you want to provide updates to your data, make any changes to your communication preferences or exercise any of your rights as outlined above, please contact us in the Development Office.
11. Changes to this Privacy NoticeThis privacy notice was last updated on 24th May 2018.
We reserve the right to update this privacy notice at any time. Any changes to this privacy notice will be posted to this page.
Christ Church, St. Aldates, Oxford, OX1 1DP, United Kingdom. Tel: +44 (0)1865 276150
